<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-04-09T21:40:45-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Brian Sun</title><subtitle></subtitle><author><name>Brian Sun</name></author><entry><title type="html">New Computer Science Degree For Toddlers Paves Way For Six-Digit Salaries</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/toddler-course/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Computer Science Degree For Toddlers Paves Way For Six-Digit Salaries" /><published>2023-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/toddler-course</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/toddler-course/">&lt;p&gt;SAN JOSE, CA — There’s a new unicorn on the block. Trailblazing e-learning start-up Bots4Tots was valued at a hefty $2.3 billion after raising $150 million in its most recent round of funding. Their product? A tailor-made two-year computer science degree for toddlers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demand for the program has been insatiable ever since Bots4Tots Academy welcomed their first class of 529 toddlers last fall. Even then, parents from San Francisco to New York City—but nowhere in between—jostled for any available seat they could find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Academy’s goal is to “nurture the next generation of big tech grunts.” To graduate, a toddler must brave a rigorous and punishing curriculum. The Bots4Tots website boasts a plan of study that “covers at least as much as the typical undergraduate computer science degree, which, as it happens, isn’t even that much, since college students aren’t learning anything these days except for how to whine and complain.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bots4Tots founder and CEO Robert Monroe was a computer science major “back in the good old days of honest work and firm handshakes.” He wistfully recalls an era when instructors had no scruples about assigning 50-hour problem sets, handing out Fs as motivation, or mocking students in front of their peers for giving the wrong answers to trick questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under Monroe’s guidance, the Academy has revived these vibrant learning environments of the past. “We will continually push our students to the brink of mental collapse—emphasis on ‘brink’—so they can be conditioned from an early age to maximize their productivity,” he stated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bots4Tots brain trust also hopes that their legions of tireless software-savvy graduates can help rehabilitate the image of America’s tech industry. Monroe himself lamented that big tech has gotten a bad rap in recent years, being portrayed as a place with a favorable work-life balance, generous employee benefits, and even time to take breaks from work to play ping-pong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They’ve become soft and, frankly, un-American. Employees should be grateful for the bountiful corporations who’ve deigned to pay them,” Monroe asserted. “Academy graduates will have internalized this idea. After all, what’s the point of education if not to mass-produce the proverbial cog in the machine?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents are all for it. In their eyes, the Academy presents a rare opportunity to take a concrete step in securing their children’s futures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jackson Rice is one of these parents. “When I was a child,” he recalled, “my parents sang the praises of a so-called ‘liberal arts education.’ I heeded their advice, only to learn that it was nothing but a treacherous pile of fool’s gold.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looks back on his college years with painful regret. “While I was moldering away in my room reading great works of world literature, my peers were taking their twenty-fifth computer science class,” Rice sighed. “Though I was a CS major, you can imagine which students were landing the most lucrative jobs. I had to settle for a $60,000 salary after graduating.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rice said he has already arranged the first twenty-two years of his son’s life: after Bots4Tots Academy will be fifteen years of five-hour-a-day tutoring (twelve hours on the weekends) till the end of high school, followed by at least forty advanced computer science courses at a top ten university. He is confident that adherence to this plan will mold his son into a reasonably competitive applicant two decades down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve talked to other parents in my network, and they’ve gone even further,” he revealed. “These days, some want their children to intern at heavy hitters like Google or Microsoft before starting kindergarten. I would never do that to my child. All that pressure could break him.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rice pays just under $80,000 a year in tuition, a figure that has sparked much controversy lately. Critics maintain that the Academy only serves the well-off, expanding the yawning chasm between rich and poor. Monroe dismissed such concerns: “All Academy graduates will end up with six-digit salaries. It pays for itself. Take out a loan if you need to. And, come on, we’re a business, so we have to profit. Rich people have money by definition, so of course we’ll inevitably cater to them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monroe might need the money. Though Bots4Tots was the first mover in the pre-preschool computer science education industry, competitors are fast emerging. Overflows4Embryos, for example, is building technology that can teach embryos how to code via ultrasound transmissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We might have another child just to try that out,” laughed Rice. “Starting their education at -8 months old is something I never even dreamed of being possible. Their employability would be off the charts.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Sun</name></author><category term="satire" /><summary type="html">SAN JOSE, CA — There’s a new unicorn on the block. Trailblazing e-learning start-up Bots4Tots was valued at a hefty $2.3 billion after raising $150 million in its most recent round of funding. Their product? A tailor-made two-year computer science degree for toddlers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To Immortalize Its Legends, Mathematics Needs a Hall of Fame</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/math-hall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To Immortalize Its Legends, Mathematics Needs a Hall of Fame" /><published>2023-03-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/math-hall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/math-hall/">&lt;p&gt;Every year, during the last week of July, baseball royalty convenes in Cooperstown, New York to commemorate the sport’s newest class of Hall of Fame inductees. It’s a warm and pensive affair. Tracts of folding chairs seat a rapt audience absorbing the wisdom of each half-hour long induction speech. For the inductees, it’s a moment seasoned with introspection, gratitude, and  surely a pinch of pride: the path to Cooperstown lies unbeaten and easily lost. Of the over 20,000 major leaguers that have embarked on the journey, only 270 have stayed the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally inaugurated as a drawing card for Depression-era Cooperstown, the National Baseball Hall of Fame now stands as the preeminent bastion of baseball lore. Its three-story museum exhibits everything from baseball movie memorabilia to an all-inclusive timeline of the game’s storied past. And of course, there’s the Plaque Gallery. Engraved in bronze are the names and faces of those legendary players who have left an indelible mark on the game, the main characters in the epic of baseball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I browsed through images of the plaques online, a thought occurred to me. What about the Bonds, Sosa, and McGwire of mathematics? Should Euclid, Euler, and Gauss be memorialized only in theorem names and Wikipedia pages? Of course not. It is indeed long past time to give genius its due: mathematics requires its own hall of fame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of mathematics is little more than the history of great individuals. Since antiquity, the contributions of the top fraction of a percent of mathematicians have laughably dwarfed those of the rest. It’s Everest versus the Eiffel Tower, Dante versus Drake. Not that any of this should be surprising to anyone. Just like baseball talent, God did not inject everyone with mathematical genius, instead choosing to inoculate a cadre of blessed souls, and even then, some with far higher dosage than others. The master Henri Poincaré put it best: “Mathematicians are born, not made.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This element makes the field particularly amenable to the idea of a hall of fame. If only a handful of these masterminds are born every generation, then we should do well in preserving their work, and their spirit, as triumphs of humanity. For us unsophisticated sorts, we can and should revere these godsends with that same deferential awe usually reserved for our deities. Mathematically, at least, no amount of hard work and perseverance could ever propel us to their distant universe. Yet if the hall of fame is to be not only a recognition of achievements, but also a celebration of lives, we would nevertheless have plenty to gain. Learning about how the greats put their talent to work, how they persisted in honing their craft, how they sacrificed for the pursuit of knowledge—their lives can teach us what it takes to succeed, perhaps on a smaller scale, or even in a different vocation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take John Forbes Nash.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In his prime, he personified what can only be called a killer instinct, sauntering into the hallowed halls of MIT with the swaggering conviction that he was the greatest geometer on earth, capable of solving any open problem in the field. When a now-forgotten professor challenged him with the isometric embedding conjecture, then considered virtually insoluble, Nash hunkered down and emerged with the seminal Nash Embedding Theorems a few short years later. We should all strive to mirror Nash’s confidence: ego is the wellspring of willpower, and ultimately, triumph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or take David Hilbert, from whom we can learn about making the ultimate sacrifice. Hilbert’s only son, Franz, was deeply unstable. After a manic episode during which Franz raved wildly about a host of malicious phantoms, Hilbert called a psychiatrist, and Franz was admitted to a nearby mental health hospital. It was here when Hilbert faced a pivotal choice: to spend his years caring for Franz, or to continue sparring with the riddles of mathematics. His decision marks an astounding conquest of biological instinct by rational resolve: “From now on,” he confided to Richard Courant, “I must consider myself as not having a son.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nash and Hilbert are just two of the many heroes who’s stories punctuate the history of mathematics. Yet if a budding mathematician wished to learn about their lives in detail, they would find no centralized, authoritative record, only a book here or a video there. A hall of fame, at the very least, would fill this informational lacuna. The institution would curate a thorough library of articles and books dedicated to the virtuosos of mathematics. It would also oversee a museum, where visitors can reflect with hushed reverence in the shadow of the hall’s inductees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a devotee of mathematics goes into raptures about a particularly elegant and beautiful result, one can usually discern a religious undertone to their speech. There’s a feeling that the proof was foreordained by a brilliant spirit, and that same spirit must have possessed the mind of the prover. This mathematical faith, if one can call it that, is pervasive. A hall of fame would offer a digital and physical home to embody this faith, showing how it inspired some of the best and brightest that humanity has ever had to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Enshrining Nash in the Cooperstown of math would be a first concrete step in completing the long-overdue task of reclaiming this wizard from the economists. Forty years after the mathematics community snubbed him of a Fields Medal, the dismal science finally cashed in its free lunch when they awarded Nash their disgrace of a Nobel Prize, tethering him to the field of economics in the public consciousness. &lt;em&gt;A Beautiful Mind&lt;/em&gt; didn’t help, either. And before you say it, no, no one has heard of the Abel Prize. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Constance Reid, &lt;em&gt;Hilbert&lt;/em&gt;, 139. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Sun</name></author><category term="math" /><category term="satire" /><summary type="html">Every year, during the last week of July, baseball royalty convenes in Cooperstown, New York to commemorate the sport’s newest class of Hall of Fame inductees. It’s a warm and pensive affair. Tracts of folding chairs seat a rapt audience absorbing the wisdom of each half-hour long induction speech. For the inductees, it’s a moment seasoned with introspection, gratitude, and surely a pinch of pride: the path to Cooperstown lies unbeaten and easily lost. Of the over 20,000 major leaguers that have embarked on the journey, only 270 have stayed the course.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Well You Really Went Bald There, Didn’t You?</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/seinfeld-bald/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Well You Really Went Bald There, Didn’t You?" /><published>2023-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/seinfeld-bald</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/seinfeld-bald/">&lt;p&gt;I was watching Seinfeld one evening when I came across a scene so exquisitely funny that I at once rewound the episode a few minutes just to watch it again. It was as if my brain didn’t fully believe the sitcom perfection that had just transpired and demanded an encore for confirmation. And confirmed it was. Later that night, during those 5-120 minutes of pre-slumbrous phone use, I rewatched the scene at least ten more times, falling asleep to its piquant repartee echoing in my brain case like the melody of a catchy new song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow me to set the stage. Jerry is dating (tormenting) a new woman, as per usual. Her name is Lois, and her boss Duncan, happens to be an old high-school acquaintance of Jerry’s.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Old wounds reopen when the former charges the latter of jumping the gun during “the big race” their sophomore year. Though Duncan speaks the truth, Jerry, ever the narcissist, simply cannot let such an accusation slide, especially not in front of Lois. He and George hatch a plan to clear his name: Jerry is to get lunch with Duncan and Lois, during which George will enter. The two will pretend to not recognize each other, and George will attest to Jerry’s version of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the backstory. Here’s the clip on YouTube, aptly labeled as one of the “Great Scenes in TV History”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GRRix62Xgx4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What struck me most about this scene besides Jason Alexander’s typically flawless acting is its inexorably deterministic trajectory. Here’s what I mean. For the determinist, once the universe sparks into existence, it issues an immutable chain of cause and effect that dictates the rest of eternity. Analogously, in this scene, once we see George gawking at Jerry like a Trekkie meeting William Shatner, the pair become two lumbering barges set on a collision course—nothing can stop the fated sequence of undermining and overreaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an open question as to why George deliberately overacted his entrance. My take is that he wants to embarrass his friend, but I could be convinced that it’s instead a vain attempt at trying to be funny. Whatever the intentions, there can only be one outcome. Jerry, the self-styled “superficial man,” cannot afford the ignominy of having any association to the bald and stocky loser braying his name. He dismisses George’s exaggerated overtures with a puzzled shrug of the shoulders: “I’m sorry?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s on. George, despite how much of a loser he is in real life, is a prideful man, and won’t let Jerry off so easily. Introductions hardly finish before he corners his prey with an innocuous but treacherous question: “So, what have you been doing with yourself?”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; With Lois and Duncan present, Jerry has no option but to tell the truth, and George pounces on him with no hesitation. He recasts himself as a member of the book-reading literati, plopping him and Jerry at opposite ends of the Harold Boom—James Corden spectrum in one fell swoop.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; He then dismisses Jerry’s observational comedy as little more than a tedious series of vapid “did you ever notice” statements. Jerry is caught in such a bind that he can only answer with a grudging “yeah, yeah, yeah.” That’s the coup de grâce. If only George could have channeled this genius into his actual life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jerry doesn’t skip a beat, however. His friendship with George has always been a cascade of taunting and one-upping, games for the psychologically deviant. I wouldn’t even be surprised if they kept score.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. So in this situation, Jerry simply cannot afford to lose—it’s hardwired into his brain. Now, he can’t best George within the bounds of small talk; George has already triumphed in that domain. He instead goes straight for the jugular, throwing any pretense of propriety out the window: “Well you really went bald there, didn’t you?”, accompanied with exaggerated gestures that evoke the “thick, full head of hair” that once graced George’s crown.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truly marvelous. There’s really not any more I can say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What follows next is entirely expected. George takes the opportunity to add “millionaire” to his trophy case (the table knock is brilliant), and a millionaire architect at that. Jerry tries to topple this edifice of lies, and as he’s ragging on George’s canvas shoes, the two entirely have forgotten their original mission. When George starts for the door, Jerry reminds him of their scheme, having the utmost confidence that George will pull through for him. And of course George does, but not without a raunchy digression about the “voluptuous homeroom teacher.” That’s true, deep friendship, expressed in a way no amount of sentimental and sickly dialogue can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve reached the end and none of it feels contrived. Having watched a considerable percentage of Seinfeld, though it’s undoubtedly one of the funniest shows I’ve ever seen, such a natural and magical moment that lasts so long (in sitcom time) without any help from the plot is nevertheless few and far between. It’s just Jerry and George and their relationship with each other, and the result is pure, natural hilarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Yes, there are Superman jokes in the episode. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’d be remiss if I didn’t acknowledge George’s all too casual dismissal of Lois. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Not sure if this so-called “spectrum” actually exists. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In one of the most memorable lines of the show, Jerry lays bare his dating philosophy: “No games? What’s the point of dating without games? How do you know if you’re winning or losing?” &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I have no doubt that this is a Larry David joke. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Sun</name></author><category term="culture" /><summary type="html">I was watching Seinfeld one evening when I came across a scene so exquisitely funny that I at once rewound the episode a few minutes just to watch it again. It was as if my brain didn’t fully believe the sitcom perfection that had just transpired and demanded an encore for confirmation. And confirmed it was. Later that night, during those 5-120 minutes of pre-slumbrous phone use, I rewatched the scene at least ten more times, falling asleep to its piquant repartee echoing in my brain case like the melody of a catchy new song.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Nine Inning Saga: Baseball Savant’s Pitch Type Guessing Game</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/savant-pitching-game/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Nine Inning Saga: Baseball Savant’s Pitch Type Guessing Game" /><published>2022-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/savant-pitching-game</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/savant-pitching-game/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the nonexistent readers of this blog, let me begin by apologizing for the dearth of activity these past three months. I’ve had to move cities, settle into a new apartment, and begin a new, terribly uninspiring job. But that’s a topic for another day.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We’re here today to discuss baseball, or more precisely, an online game derived from the game of baseball. And some data science, too. And perhaps a congeries of other random things. This is a post that has idled on the assembly line for over two and a half months, so it’s about time I present the finished product. Let’s begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On an ordinary mid-July evening, I was lifelessly snooping around &lt;a href=&quot;baseballsavant.mlb.com&quot;&gt;Baseball Savant&lt;/a&gt; after a relatively anemic performance by my beloved Cleveland Guardians: for the second night in a row, they had failed to score a single earned run against the pathetically mediocre Chicago White Sox.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Then came the epochal event. Hovering my cursor over the 3x3 grid of tiny black squares at the top right corner of the page, a menu popped up, and my gaze instantly fixed on the seductive “Savant Games” link. As I moved to click it, my mind raked up old memories of high-school me playing the notoriously difficult &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.disney--games.com/winnie_the_pooh_s_home_run_derby_338.html&quot;&gt;Winnie the Pooh’s Home Run Derby&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Looking back now, this flash of remembrance was a most befitting portent of what was to come. I launched the first game on the list, the seemingly innocuous Pitch Type Guessing Game. Little did I know, this wily, infernal PTGG would induce levels of rage and vexation that can only be matched by watching the Cleveland Browns inventing new ways to snatch defeat from the jaws of victory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a screenshot of the game. It’s quite simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/PTGG.png&quot; alt=&quot;PTGG&quot; class=&quot;callout&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;If you&apos;re wondering, this was a changeup.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the left there’s a pitch gif (say this ten times fast) that will keep looping itself into eternity until a guess is entered; there’s no timer or anything. On the right are the seven choices. Apologies to eephus fans in advance. The game shows twenty pitches total, and your score is just the number, or percentage, of pitches you correctly identify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a few hours to kill, you can play the game at this &lt;a href=&quot;https://baseballsavant.mlb.com/games/pitch-type-guess&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. Disclaimer: if you’re a binge-watching, achievement-grabbing neurotic like myself, proceed at your own risk. Oh yeah, throughout this post I may or may not abbreviate some pitch types with their two letter shorthand, so here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mlb.com/glossary/pitch-types&quot;&gt;dictionary&lt;/a&gt; just in case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest—before I discovered this game I mainly just thought of pitches as fastballs, sliders, and curveballs. I knew that sinkers, cutters, and splitters existed, but I never felt the need to look into their peculiarities as they all just looked fastball-esque to me. I didn’t have the foresight to jot down my score the first time I played the game, but if I had to guess it lied somewhere around 35%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having failed the practice test, I tossed some searches into Google and rummaged through a potpourri of videos, articles, blogs, and random websites run by random high school baseball coaches (which were honestly quite helpful) to hone my pitch discernment skills. Here’s a well-made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1FTFWzcgjHE&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube that I found pretty useful.  And for the sake of completeness, here’s a nice &lt;a href=&quot;https://lokeshdhakar.com/baseball-pitches-illustrated/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; I stumbled upon that depicts roughly what things look like from the catcher’s point of view.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the middle of this learning process, something amusingly ironic occurred: what was unbelievably useless and in fact actively detrimental was the MLB website’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mlb.com/news/identifying-pitch-types-a-fan-s-guide&quot;&gt;“Identifying pitch types: A fan’s guide.”&lt;/a&gt; Scroll down to the “Cutter” heading, and there’s a video of “Dodgers closer Kenley Jansen throwing a nasty one for a game-ending strikeout.” I literally watched the video like ten times, trying to cope with the ball’s vertical-diagonal break more characteristic of a slider. Then I realized that there was no Dodger in the video, the pitcher was not Kenley Jansen, and we were not at the end of the game. We were in the heart of the game. The pitcher was Jon Gray, and the video was from his tenure on the Rockies. Jon Gray doesn’t even throw a cutter. That pitch was a slider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scrolling through the rest of the article with an eye alert for trouble, I discovered that roughly half of the clips had literally nothing to do with their so-called descriptions. Perhaps a change in the backend caused the video IDs to get all scrambled up or something—who knows. What I do know is that readers who are not fully focused may leave the page more confused than they entered it. But I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to take a brief moment to showcase two pitch gifs that are emblematic of how infuriating the PTGG can be. Due to how the videos are loaded or something the one’s shown below are slightly longer than the loop you’d see in the actual game, but whatever.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;video controls=&quot;&quot; preload=&quot;none&quot; playsinline=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/CutawayFastball.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot; /&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/CutawayFastball.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Bases loaded down 14 in the 5th inning, nice.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, this wasn’t Savant’s fault, it was the fault of the
broadcasters. Guess they really wanted that replay. But really the only
option here was to go off speed, so I guessed some type of fastball and
was too absentminded to record whether or not I was right. When I’d be
on a guessing streak and a clip like this popped up, I’d get really
sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the other:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;video controls=&quot;&quot; preload=&quot;none&quot; playsinline=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/Sidearm.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot; /&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/Sidearm.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The COVID season, what a time.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we have a sidewinder here, and I have no idea how to read them.
Based on release point most of their pitches barely have any vertical
break at all (at least on the broadcast), so I’d usually just throw out
a wild guess based on speed. In this case, it was 81 mph, and I saw the
ball drop a little bit, so I vacillated between slider and curveball
and ultimately pulled the trigger on slider. It was a fastball. I don’t
have proof, but I’m not lying. It was classified as a fastball, and
that really made me question everything I knew about the
world.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;5&quot;&gt;5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For about two days, I sat lifeless, slouched in my chair, guessing at pitch types over and over and over again. Sinker, slider, and sinker again. Every once in a while I’d record my stats, which yielded just over eighteen games of data when it was all said and done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I disclose my mediocre results, let me mention that an encyclopedic knowledge of exactly what pitches every pitcher throws, what range of speeds they throw it at, and so on, would have been a massive boon to me. I did not (and still do not) possess such knowledge off the top of my head, and the chivalric part of my soul felt that I would besmirch my honor if I pulled up each pitcher’s Savant profile before guessing. With that being said, here are my percentages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/PTGG_Percentages.png&quot; alt=&quot;PTGG Percentages&quot; class=&quot;callout&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Yes, this is a prebuilt theme from Excel.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t look like I improved at all over the course of the experiment, which, if my memory doesn’t fail me, is congruent with how I felt during those two days. Though to be fair to myself, I did achieve results of 90% and 95% a few times–it just so happened that I didn’t record them.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s check my platoon splits. I batted .600 against lefties and .637 against righties, which honestly surprised me quite a bit. The oblique camera angle typical of baseball broadcasts made it much easier to identify movement from right-handed pitchers. In many cases I could never distinguish between a four-seamer and a sinker when it came a southpaw, as it was basically impossible to see how much run a pitch had relative to its release point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example. T.J. McFarland, leftie, pitching for the Athletics in 2020:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;video controls=&quot;&quot; preload=&quot;none&quot; playsinline=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/McFarland.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot; /&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/McFarland.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;For some reason I recorded this using QuickTime instead of downloading the video like I usually did.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first glance, the trajectory looks slider-like. But it’s simply too fast, and I’ve never heard of McFarland, so if I have to guess he’s probably no Gerrit Cole or Emmanuel Clasé. So it’s either a four-seamer or a sinker. Which one is it? I literally have no idea. Maybe you guess sinker because it sinks, but every ball sinks on its way to the plate. Maybe you can look at the color of the ball to determine the spin, or something. I guessed sinker, it happened to be a sinker, but I was far from confident in my choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;6&quot;&gt;6.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pairs of pitches I was most likely to confuse for each other were FF &amp;amp; SI and SL &amp;amp; CU. Apropos of the first pair, there are some cases where it’s quite easy to identify a sinker. For example, take the following pitch by Jonathan Hernandez:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s that unmistakable torsion in its movement that will basically never exist for a four-seamer. Other times though, depending on the whims of the camera angle, I found it borderline impossible to distinguish between the two fastballs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d say I’m noticeably better at maneuvering the SL &amp;amp; CU mix-up. In fact, to get an impression of my classification skills, we can form the confusion matrices for FF &amp;amp; SI and SL &amp;amp; CU.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/Confusion.png&quot; alt=&quot;Confusion matrices&quot; class=&quot;callout&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Couldn&apos;t quite figure out how to format the table in markdown.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly not that great. If the gamed showed sinker, I’d guess four-seamer about 45% of the time. Perhaps I’m relying too much on the twisting motion of the baseball to identify sinkers, when in reality many of them may only exhibit a far more muted version of it. For real curveballs I’d be wrong almost 30% of the time, which isn’t that great either. If I had to guess this is probably a product of how my mental image of a “mean curve” is Clayton Kershaw’s, and his curveball has had consistently more vertical break than the average. At least I had good and acceptable performances for the four-seamer and slider respectively, which I’ll take as a win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;7&quot;&gt;7&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a day of spamming the game over and over again, I nurtured a dubious hunch that ultimately grew into a full-on suspicion: there was simply no chance the distribution of pitches I encountered in the PTGG tallied with the true distribution of pitches in the MLB. I felt that at the very least there was an overabundance of sinkers and an insufficiency of cutters. And maybe an undersupply of changeups as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hypothesis was backed up by the data. Using statistics gleaned from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pitcherlist.com&quot;&gt;Pitcher List&lt;/a&gt;, we can calculate the distribution of pitch types from this season.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  Here’s the table, labeled with that two-letter shorthand I alluded to earlier:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/PitchList.png&quot; alt=&quot;Confusion matrices&quot; class=&quot;callout&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;That&apos;s actually way more pitches than I expected.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “UN” label stands for “Unknown.” Given that they make up a meager 0.05% of all pitches thrown, for the sake of simplicity (and at the expense of statistical integrity) I’m going to continue my analysis pretending they don’t exist, as the PTGG is never gonna hit me with one of them. But I would be curious to see a video of one of these pitches—are they made up of wild, feral pitches, strange grips, or something else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So splitters are diamonds, sinkers are gold, curveballs and changeups are silver, cutters and sliders are bronze, and the old reliable four-seam fastball is iron or some other abundant metal. Looking at this data, I can tell you right off the bat&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:10&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:10&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that the pitches thrown in the PTGG do not reflect these percentages at all. Here’s the distribution I got from the approximately 18 games that I took notes for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/PTGGDist.png&quot; alt=&quot;Confusion matrices&quot; class=&quot;callout&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The fact that I didn&apos;t get a single splitter is pretty
impressive.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two distributions are worlds part and the specifics of how they differ are pretty much in line with what my intuition told me.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:11&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:11&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We can run a basic &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chi-squared_test&quot;&gt;chi-squared test&lt;/a&gt; to quantify this gap. The resulting p-value is 5.18 * 10e-35. That’s a lot of significance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we can observe the nefarious PTGG designers at work. We already talked about how the hardest pitch I had trouble identifying correctly was the sinker: out of 76 sinkers seen, I mistakenly classified a whopping 34 of them as four-seam fastballs. And looking at the data, it seems like the PTGG has more than tripled the number of sinkers at the expense of savagely slashing the number of cutters, which are certainly easier to identify, given their usual slower speed and slight glove-side movement. Was this game purposely designed to make my life more miserable? I have no idea, but honestly this is as compelling evidence as there can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;8&quot;&gt;8&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fanatical, egotistical, and megalomaniacal parts of my brain (all three parts, in other words) could not endure the humiliation of still getting Bs and Cs and Fs on this exam despite retaking it at least a hundred times. “What if it’s Savant’s classification that’s wrong?,” I bargained.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:12&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:12&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Such thoughts goaded me into looking up how Savant even determines what these pitches are in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first articles I stumbled upon was this &lt;a href=&quot;https://technology.mlblogs.com/mlb-pitch-classification-64a1e32ee079&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; from the MLB Technology Blog, which contained everything I wanted and then some. The innards of pitch classification are exactly what you’d expect. Lots and lots of data. Unsupervised learning. A neural network named PitchNet. Now, I’m not going to profess knowledge of whatever XGBoost is, but I think there are some things worth considering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a high level, there’s a dangerous pitfall that all machine learning algorithms must skirt in some way, and that’s the fact that they may be unwittingly eating their own tail. More precisely, the output of the algorithm may be influencing the environment it operates in, which influences its inputs (the training data), which in turn influences its output, which in turn … you get the idea. If this self-perpetuating cycle is left to spin around on its own, there may be perverse, potentially destructive outcomes, depending on the use case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of PitchNet, the question that springs to mind is the following: where does its training data come from? Theoretically it should consist of the myriad pitches thrown every night during baseball season, but those pitches are identified immediately by Statcast using … PitchNet. There must be some exogenous source of truth, and despite the aid of a clustering algorithm, what really matters is what the pitcher says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We classify each pitch in each pitcher’s repertoire as the pitcher himself calls it; for instance, a pitch that one pitcher calls a cutter may be called a slider by another, even if the velocity, spin, and movement of both pitches are essentially identical. Direct quotes from the pitchers themselves, as well as from pitching coaches, managers, and other on-field staff, are used to verify each pitcher’s repertoire along with images of the pitchers using different pitch grips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s a slider? Sure, it’s a breaking ball, faster than a curveball, slower than a fastball, and breaks glove-side. But at the end of the day, it seems that a slider is whatever a pitcher thinks is a slider. So now we have another reason why the PTGG can be so damn vexing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;9&quot;&gt;9&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple days I came to accept my leaves-much-to-be-desired pitch classification skills. My eyes, it seemed, were simply not as keen as those of PitchNet. I resolved to vulgarize things: out with the four-seamer, two-seamer, sinker, slider, and curveball. Fastball and breaking ball were all I needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, maybe. I had one final dalliance with the old PTGG to scrape a few videos for this post, and something did happen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/100.png&quot; alt=&quot;100%&quot; class=&quot;callout&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;I don&apos;t remember how it happened exactly, but I probably
got 15 four-seam fastballs or something.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A perfect game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;If you’re one of my coworkers, please understand that you’re basically the only thing between me and madness. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;As I’m writing this, we just lost a tough five-game ALDS to the Yankees. We’ll be back next year. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It’s basically impossible to beat Christopher Robin. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I think this guy is a UI designer; his blog is really cool. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;If none of the videos from here on out load, I apologize. Try another browser maybe. I was running into issues with Chrome that I had no idea how to fix. Aargh. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Turns out that the pitcher is &lt;a href=&quot;https://baseballsavant.mlb.com/savant-player/brian-moran-57238&quot;&gt;Brian Moran&lt;/a&gt;. He debuted in 2019, is 34 years old (probably what they’re talking about in the video), and in fact, throws an 82mph fastball. In 2020 he threw 110 pitches for a 9.26 ERA. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Don’t think I dipped below 35%, at least. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You might protest that this analysis excludes the times when the pitch was FF and I guessed FC, for example. Two things to note: first, on fastballs I usually always guessed FF or SI, as FC rarely showed up in the game (this will be analyzed in the next section); second, SL and CU pitches usually have enough break that I would basically never guess anything else. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Okay, I lied. I actually did this calculation in late-July, when I first broke ground on this post—so there’s only about a half season’s worth of data. You might also object that the PTGG has pitches from as early as the 2020 season; to that I agree, but as we will soon see the discrepancy is so large that I am more than confident that expanding the dataset would yield little to no change. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:10&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Sorry. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:10&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:11&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You may wonder if Pitcher List has a classification method distinct from that of the MLB. I seriously doubt that’s the case, as the MLB has access to exclusive data captured directly at ballparks that no third party tool could even dream of having. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:11&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:12&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is some variant of that Seymour Skinner meme. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:12&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Sun</name></author><category term="baseball" /><summary type="html">1 To the nonexistent readers of this blog, let me begin by apologizing for the dearth of activity these past three months. I’ve had to move cities, settle into a new apartment, and begin a new, terribly uninspiring job. But that’s a topic for another day.1 We’re here today to discuss baseball, or more precisely, an online game derived from the game of baseball. And some data science, too. And perhaps a congeries of other random things. This is a post that has idled on the assembly line for over two and a half months, so it’s about time I present the finished product. Let’s begin. If you’re one of my coworkers, please understand that you’re basically the only thing between me and madness. &amp;#8617;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The End of Childhood</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/childhood/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The End of Childhood" /><published>2022-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/childhood</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/childhood/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay is based on my own, personal experiences, written amid a rush of nostalgia. There were moments in our childhoods that I’m sure everyone has had, when things were not looking so great, and we fell into the caress of the abyss. I’m not going to talk about any of that in here, for better or for worse.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a little over two weeks, I’m going to move into an apartment and start a full-time job. And with that, I know, will come the end of my childhood. For years I and countless other kids have been warned by the more hardened members of our species about this so-called “real world.” And for years it seemed like something that was forever distant, like that light at the end of a long tunnel—always a speck no matter how many steps you take in its direction. But before you know it, that speck will expand, and expand, and soon you’ll feel the sun mercilessly beating down on your head. Welcome to the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t say that I’m not scared. In fact I’m terrified. Terrified of having to go to work every day, terrified of having to do my own taxes, terrified of having to bicker with a nasty landlord. Terrified of pure, genuine, adulthood. That’s literally the reality for billions of people, you might respond, and to that I agree. But I can’t deny my feelings—they are also real, and they are a reflection of my cowardice, my naïveté, my privilege, and my doomed realization that the blissful way of life that I have been living—the only way of life I have ever known—has finally reached its expiration date. So before I take this last step across the threshold of adulthood and close the door behind me, I want to pause in this liminal moment, turn myself around, and steal just one last glance at those fun and scary and glorious days of being a child, as a child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My very first memory is not some enchanting dialogue with my parents, nor some jolly adventure with a fellow toddler: it’s me cheerfully pronouncing to my grandparents, in Mandarin, that I indeed have to poop. I have often wondered why my brain chose this particular moment to inaugurate its long-term storage, but looking back now, it seems a most felicitous choice. There’s the unwarranted self-importance, the unbridled exuberance, and of course, the mention of poop, a staple in the genre of little kid humor. And I think that about sums up those earliest years of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the formative elementary school years. There’s so many vivid memories. The first day of kindergarten. Discovering that my friend from first-grade lives only three houses down from me. Climbing into the sewer tunnel in my backyard. Playing freeze tag during recess. Catching frogs and toads in the woods. Waking up before my parents on the weekends to go downstairs and watch whatever was on Nickelodeon and play Pokémon on my DS. Reading &lt;em&gt;Magic Tree House&lt;/em&gt;. Dialing 911 on an apparently unplugged phone and hiding when the cops show up. Wondering why the sky is blue, why everyone else is taller than me, and why the goddamn tooth fairy never showed up to my house. And the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those were the years of youthful exuberance, the years when ignorance truly meant bliss. Nothing really mattered back then, regardless of what our melodramatic ten-year-old minds believed. We were never going to marry that girl down the street, nor were we ever going to fight that kid who cut us in line. Our anger at a friend would subside the next day and our lost basketball would be replaced with a brand new one by the end of the week. We were the center of the universe, and it seemed that the universe (or in many cases our parents) took care of us: carefree living at its finest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a sense that everything changes come middle school and high school. That’s true in many ways, as adolescence is surely a different beast. We endure the crucible of puberty, discover our own sexuality, and develop a nascent social awareness, an awareness that the contours of our hair and the brands of our socks may actually matter. But these are still the years of childhood. Just think about it—what really happened during those youthful times? The endless cat and mouse of teenage relationship drama, the turbulent bus rides of school field trips, and the superabundance of unabashedly crude jokes. Of course it was not all so rosy, given the rampant bullying and backbiting, not to mention the tyranny of the cliques. But above all of this petty nonsense, it was a time of growth, bonding, and exploration, of meeting up at Denny’s in the middle of the night, of cramming for exams I should’ve studied for weeks before, of vibing for hours and hours with my closest friends. Because at the end of the day, we were all just kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;College: the last hurrah. Sure, there was more responsibility to take on, but it was nothing that hadn’t been done before—doing the laundry, cleaning my room, maybe even cooking a little. But more importantly, and I am quite sure of this, it was the most free that I ever have been, and probably ever will be. Academics, admittedly, probably took up much more time than I had hoped, but that doesn’t detract at all from those magical four years during which I had the license to do whatever the hell I wanted. I could go with my friends to pick up slightly above average pizza at 2AM, haunt the nearby pumpkin patch with my girlfriend, lose all of my money playing poker, complain to unsuspecting listeners about the futility of life, or spend five hours a day watching my suitemates play Bloons Tower Defense. And I would wake up the next morning knowing that all of these options and more were once again readily available, that my friends were just a short walk away, just as excited as I am to see what lies ahead on this new, unsullied day. Happy times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a constant strand that strings together those years of life from my very first memory to these last few weeks before my new job. I can’t quite place my finger on it, but I know it’s there, and I know it relates to a most essential question: what is childhood all about? I’m not looking for a scientific or an academic answer, naturally, but instead one that simply feels right, something that has to do with that idyllic coalescence of freedom, levity, and unadulterated joy. And honestly, I don’t think there’s anything better than saying that childhood, for me at least, is exactly what I have written above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the classic clichés of the English language roughly goes as follows: “You don’t know what you have until it’s gone.” Like most clichés, though it’s overused, it still contains a kernel of truth. So perhaps I can’t really know what being a child is about right now, as I have yet to take that last step into the world of permanent adulthood. But when the time comes, I will reflect, and I will find out. For just like those brilliant, sublime constellations of the night sky, my childhood will always be there, unreachable, yet shining all the same.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Sun</name></author><category term="reflections" /><summary type="html">This essay is based on my own, personal experiences, written amid a rush of nostalgia. There were moments in our childhoods that I’m sure everyone has had, when things were not looking so great, and we fell into the caress of the abyss. I’m not going to talk about any of that in here, for better or for worse.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Aristotle’s _Poetics_ and the Tragic Hero</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/aristotle-poetics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aristotle’s _Poetics_ and the Tragic Hero" /><published>2022-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/aristotle-poetics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/aristotle-poetics/">&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/Epidaurus.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Theater of Epidaurus&quot; class=&quot;callout&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The Ancient Theater of Epidaurus. Look at those mountains.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, this post was going to have three parts, one for each of Sophocles’ three Theban plays: &lt;em&gt;Antigone&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Oedipus Rex&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Oedipus at Colonus&lt;/em&gt;. I soon discovered that I am simply too slow of a writer to complete anything of that sorts in a reasonable amount of time, so I then decided to focus solely on &lt;em&gt;Antigone&lt;/em&gt;, and in particular, the tragic arcs of Antigone and Creon. When I was prewriting, I found a quote from Aristotle’s &lt;em&gt;Poetics&lt;/em&gt; that I wanted to use, which I did. As that literary-theoretical(?) section slowly grew into its own beast, I realized that I would never complete anything if I didn’t force myself to stop the drafting process, so I cut out almost everything &lt;em&gt;Antigone&lt;/em&gt;-related and now what we’re left with is some stuff about Aristotle’s &lt;em&gt;Poetics&lt;/em&gt;. The resulting argument is much less interesting than what it could’ve been, and probably has at least a few holes. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Aristotelian Theory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aristotle’s &lt;em&gt;Poetics&lt;/em&gt;, according to Wikipedia, is the “first extant philosophical treatise to focus on literary theory.” Much of the work has been lost to history, and almost all of what has survived concerns Attic tragedy. For the remainder of this post, I will analyze some of what the &lt;em&gt;Poetics&lt;/em&gt; has to say about crafting the perfect tragic hero. I’ll only be citing two paragraphs (from &lt;a href=&quot;http://classics.mit.edu/Aristotle/poetics.1.1.html&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; English translation), but even that is more than enough material to ruminate on.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We’ll begin with the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A perfect tragedy, should, as we have seen, be arranged not on the simple but on the complex plan. It should, moreover, imitate actions which excite pity and fear, this being the distinctive mark of tragic imitation. It follows plainly, in the first place, that the change of fortune presented must not be the spectacle of a virtuous man brought from prosperity to adversity: for this moves neither pity nor fear; it merely shocks us. Nor, again, should the downfall of the utter villain be exhibited. A plot of this kind, would, doubtless, satisfy the moral sense, but it would inspire neither pity nor fear; for pity is aroused by unmerited misfortune, fear by the misfortune of a man like ourselves. Such an event, therefore, will be neither pitiful nor terrible. There remains, then, the character between these two extremes—that of a man who is not eminently good and just, yet whose misfortune is brought about not by vice or depravity, but by some error or frailty (Part XIII).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a long one, but it’s worth dissecting. Aristotle posits that the emotional aim of tragedy is to elicit in the spectators a catharsis of pity and fear. There’s no way to justify this assumption, but I’m sure most of us can agree, at the very least, that tragedy and pity—the feeling “aroused by unmerited misfortune”—should be inseparable bedfellows. And fear, in this case, carries a connotation closer to terror, a “terrible” realization that a variation of what’s playing out onstage could very well happen to “a man like ourselves.” It seems reasonable that tragedy should arouse this brand of fear.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  Moving forward, Aristotle then censures two character arcs for failing to live up to tragic expectations: the “virtuous man brought from prosperity to adversity” and the “downfall of the utter villain.” As these two extremes mark the boundaries of what counts as an acceptable tragic hero, it is worth scrutinizing their respective shortcomings in detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-virtuous-man&quot;&gt;The Virtuous Man&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The destruction of the “virtuous man,” Aristotle writes, “moves neither pity nor fear; it merely shocks us.” Such a statement may feel a little off target. It is natural to view the misfortunes of the virtuous—whether due to an “act of God” or the malicious offense of some wrongdoer—as essentially tragic, arousing a flood of pity for the victims and a fear that such a fate could one day be our own, sensations directly at odds with Aristotle’s claims. The only way to salvage his argument, it seems, is to mire ourselves in an endless and fruitless debate over the definitions of “pity” and “fear,” which I’d really like to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s do that, and direct our attention to a word that has quietly slipped under the radar: “virtuous.” Now, I don’t know Ancient Greek, unfortunately, so instead of appealing to the source text the best I can do is pull up an English definition of the word in the American Heritage Dictionary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;virtuous&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;adj&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;. Having or showing virtue, especially moral excellence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’ve discovered, to no one’s surprise, is that the “virtuous man” is the moral man. And if the hallmark of the moral man is that they always make the right decision, then their downfall brings up a question of just deserts: a paragon of virtue, tautologically, does not deserve any of the misfortune that the omnipotent poet can burden them with. It is this omission of causation, culpability, and responsibility that mars the quality of the pity and fear that the spectators feel in such situations. And so we are led to another section of the &lt;em&gt;Poetics&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As in the structure of the plot, so too in portraiture of character, the poet should always aim either at the necessary or the probable. Thus a person of a given character should speak or act in a given way, by the rule either of necessity or of probability; just as this event should follow that by necessary or probable sequence. It is therefore evident that the unraveling of the plot, no less than the complication, must arise out of the plot itself . . . (Part XV).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we watch a play, we want the events that unfold onstage to happen for a reason—they should be “the necessary or the probable.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The reason for this, I think, is the following: random and indiscriminate dismantling of the protagonist shatters the belief that there is some sort of order in the universe, that there is some mystical and cosmic force that rewards the virtuous and condemns the wicked. Though such an attitude may seem irrational and naïve in our post-Enlightenment era, it was certainly the norm for those living in Ancient Greece.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; From their corpus of myths to the epics of Homer, we’ve learned that their gods held human emotions and (usually) governed with a sense of justice. To destroy the “virtuous man,” then, is to deny the power of the Greek pantheon. And that is unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we can return to that original paragraph from the &lt;em&gt;Poetics&lt;/em&gt; and look at it from a new angle. When Aristotle writes that the tragic hero’s misfortunes should be “brought about not by vice or depravity, but by some error or frailty,” what we notice is the implicit role of responsibility, that their agonies are in some way correlated with the “error or frailty” of their actions. Without such a link, the play would no longer be tragic, but instead only unreasonable and unbelievable, a procession of existential sorrows that “merely shock us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-utter-villain&quot;&gt;The Utter Villain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onto the “downfall of the utter villain.” Aristotle objects to this device on the grounds that it elicits neither pity nor fear.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I’m sure we can all agree with the lack of pity in such a scenario, but let’s ponder over why there is a lack of fear. There’s two possible explanations: (1) Aristotle holds a tremendously warm view of humanity—although people may make grave mistakes, they never stoop down to the level of the “utter villain”, or (2) no person ever views themselves as such. Now I’m quite optimistic about humanity myself, but I’m fairly certain that (2) is the implied argument here. The play is meant to be judged by spectators—in the Greek case during the annual &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dionysia&quot;&gt;Dionysia&lt;/a&gt;—and hence their feelings are paramount. If the people don’t identify with the character, then they don’t. There’s no fear. End of discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s a fairly significant phrase in the text that I’ve skipped over: the undoing of the villain, Aristotle writes, will doubtlessly “satisfy the moral sense.” And this is another thing we can all agree on. Call it karma, poetic justice, or whatever—one simply cannot resist the schadenfreude of watching the wrongdoer’s demise, whether it happens in real life or on the stage. This fiendish delight, however, is exactly what the veteran poet avoids arousing. Maybe I’m just speaking for my own twisted mind here, but I feel it’s easy for even a twinge of schadenfreude to dominate my feelings, relegating all other emotions to the backseat, including those tragic sensations of pity and fear. As humans we are seemingly pre-packaged with an innate desire to see that the world is just, and it is precisely because this proclivity is so overriding that the tragedian must steer clear of the “downfall of the utter villain” lest the play become a parable rather than a tragedy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-goldilocks-zone&quot;&gt;The Goldilocks Zone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quintessential tragic hero, then, lies somewhere between the virtuous man and the utter villain. They are “not eminently good and just,” and someone “whose misfortune is brought about not by vice or depravity, but by some error or frailty.” Herein lies the ultimate challenge of the tragic poet: finding the narrow Goldilocks zone where the tragic hero must fall. The hero should be condemned, but not as a villain. They can be exalted, but not as a paragon. They must be faulty, but not evil, respectable, but not incorruptible. They’ll do wrong and pay for it, and we will pity them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I honestly can’t think another way to put it without resorting to specific examples.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I was originally going to write about how both Antigone and Creon from Sophocles’ &lt;em&gt;Antigone&lt;/em&gt; represent the archetypal tragic hero, though to reach such a conclusion one should try to put themselves in the shoes of a 500 B.C. Athenian when reading the play. There was a much stronger loyalty to the state back then than what many of us may be comfortable with today, and that certainly colors the reading of the play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave you with one last thought. You might think, after all of this, that &lt;em&gt;Oedipus Rex&lt;/em&gt;, the doomed tale of Oedipus’ discovery of his own identity, doesn’t fit into this theory at all. What, if any, of Oedipus’ misfortunes attributable to his intentions? Is he not the definition of a virtuous man who falls from grace, from exalted king to blind exile? I believe I have an answer to these questions, but it should be something pretty interesting to think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Again, I had to restrain myself. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m not sure if the Aristotelian “man” can refer to a female antecedent. Someone like Antigone (of &lt;i&gt;Antigone&lt;/i&gt;) should probably be within the scope of his analysis. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Aristotle condemned the Deus ex Machina in precisely these terms. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In a way, this means that the purview of tragedy has expanded vastly since the time of the Ancient Greeks. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Recall that pity is “unmerited misfortune” and fear is “the misfortune of a man like ourselves.” &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;At this point, I have literally read like four Attic tragedies. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Brian Sun</name></author><category term="literature" /><summary type="html">The Ancient Theater of Epidaurus. Look at those mountains.</summary></entry></feed>